UNDERCOVER MISS HONG
언더커버 미스홍
The birth of Dolly, the lamb cloned through genetic engineering…
복제양 돌리의 탄생 유전공학을 통해...
which demonstrated the possibility of human cloning,
시연 인간 복제 가능성
and the successful landing of a space probe on Mars
그리고 성공적인 착륙 화성의 우주 탐사선
all happened in 1997.
모두 1997년에 일어났습니다.
THE THIRD "COLLAPSE"
세 번째 "붕괴"
As the new millennium dawned,
새천년이 밝아오면서
the world readied itself amid great excitement and anxieties.
세계는 스스로 준비했습니다 큰 흥분과 불안 속에서.
THE THIRD WAVE
제3의 물결
CHO DU-PAL
조두팔
And there was a woman
그리고 여자가 있었어요
who sought a stunning turnaround, stirring up waves of her own.
놀라운 변화를 추구한 자신만의 파도를 일으키고 있습니다.
What else? I'm working.
또 뭐야? 나는 일하고 있습니다.
I'm on my way.
지금 가는 중이에요.
The Pitbull is on its way.
핏불이 오는 중입니다.
We can trust the witness, right?
증인을 믿을 수 있겠죠?
Of course. The witness is one smart cookie.
물론. 증인은 하나의 스마트 쿠키입니다.
All it takes is one word from me, and it'll be done.
제가 한 마디만 하면 됩니다. 그리고 완료될 것입니다.
To secure your acquittal, Mr. Cho,
당신의 무죄를 보장하기 위해, 조씨는
the Financial Supervisory Service
금융감독원
will stand by you throughout.
내내 당신 곁에 있을 것입니다.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Hey!
여기요!
You should have makeup and a skirt on.
화장을 하고 치마를 입어야 합니다.
How unprofessional.
얼마나 비전문적입니까?
Wait, Mr. Cho.
잠깐만요, 조 선생님.
- She doesn't work here. - No?
- 그녀는 여기서 일하지 않아요. - 아니요?
She's the witness I mentioned earlier.
아까 말한 증인이에요.
Gosh.
이런.
Should I leave?
떠나야 할까요?
- No, don't leave! - No!
- 아니, 떠나지 마세요! - 아니요!
Coming in.
들어옵니다.
Let's all have a drink!
다들 한잔 합시다!
- Here we go. - Excellent.
- 간다. - 훌륭한.
I would've chosen somewhere else if I had known you were a woman.
난 다른 곳을 선택했을 거에요 당신이 여자인 걸 내가 알았더라면.
Not at all, Mr. Cho.
전혀 그렇지 않아요, 조 선생님.
Don't be fooled by her looks. She's a total dude.
그녀의 외모에 속지 마세요. 그녀는 완전 친구입니다.
She's no woman.
그 사람은 여자가 아니거든요.
All right then.
그럼요.
Here comes something major.
여기에 중요한 것이 있습니다.
You can't change your tune tomorrow.
내일은 곡을 바꿀 수 없습니다.
You heard that, right?
그거 들었지?
Yes, of course.
물론이죠.
You know how I do.
내가 어떻게 하는지 당신도 알잖아요.
The stage is perfectly set for tomorrow.
내일을 위한 무대는 완벽하게 준비되었습니다.
"I swear by my conscience to speak the whole truth
"양심으로 맹세해요. 진실을 전부 말하다
and nothing but the truth."
그리고 진실 외에는 아무것도 없습니다."
"Should I lie, I shall accept punishment for perjury."
"거짓말을 해야 할까? 위증죄로 처벌 받겠다”
I am Hong Keum-bo from
저는 홍금보 출신입니다.
the Capital Market Investigation Division at the Financial Supervisory Service.
자본시장조사과 금융감독원에서.
The prosecution alleges
검찰은 주장한다
that Mr. Cho Du-pal manipulated the stock price of MU Holdings,
조두팔 씨가 조작한 것 MU홀딩스의 주가,
but is it truly illegal to buy an undervalued blue-chip stock low
그런데 구매하는 것이 정말 불법인가요? 저평가된 우량주 최저
and sell it at the upper limit?
상한가에 팔아?
What do you think, Ms. Hong?
홍 선생님은 어떻게 생각하세요?
WITNESS
증인
It's blatant stock price manipulation
노골적인 주가조작이다
by combining corporate and financial violations.
법인을 결합하여 금융 위반.
Ms. Hong,
홍 선생님,
please be reminded that you're our witness.
상기시켜주세요 당신이 우리의 증인이라는 걸요.
"Our" witness?
"우리"의 증인이요?
PROSECUTOR
검사
CHO DU-PAL
조두팔
- Are you Mr. Kim? - Yes.
- 김 선생님이신가요? - 예.
And the merch?
상품은요?
Let's grab a drink somewhere nice.
좋은 곳에서 한잔 하자.
As you can see, Mr. Cho Du-pal
보시다시피 조두팔씨는
was tipped off by an MU Holdings insider through back channels,
MU Holdings 내부자로부터 제보를 받았습니다. 백 채널을 통해,
and used it to line his own pockets.
그리고 그것을 자신의 주머니에 넣는 데 사용했습니다.
I hereby submit evidence demonstrating the procurement of funds
본인은 이에 증거를 제출합니다. 자금 조달을 보여주기
to manipulate the stock price of MU Holdings
조작하다 MU홀딩스 주가
and the funneling of illicit profits through other corporate entities.
그리고 불법적인 이익의 유입 다른 법인을 통해.
And one more thing.
그리고 한 가지 더.
I'd also like to submit evidence of him paying off
나도 증거자료 제출하고싶다 그 사람이 돈을 갚는 중
a Financial Supervisory Service employee.
금융감독원 직원입니다.
Hold on!
기다리다!
You're no cop or prosecutor.
당신은 경찰이나 검사가 아닙니다.
Who are you to act up?
당신은 누구입니까?
I'd watch that tone of yours.
나는 당신의 그 말투를 지켜보고 싶습니다.
Why you little…
왜 꼬마야...
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
Calm down.
진정하다.
Please calm down.
진정하세요.
Calm down!
진정하다!
Please calm down!
진정하세요!
SEOUL SOUTHERN DISTRICT COURT
서울남부지방법원
Damn it!
젠장!
Hey, Hong!
안녕, 홍!
What was that about?
그게 무슨 내용이었어?
You blew it at the last moment!
마지막 순간에 망쳤잖아!
Sir, what about the money--
선생님, 돈은 어떻습니까?
What?
무엇?
Damn you!
젠장!
Hold on. That's my money.
기다리다. 그건 내 돈이에요.
My money…
내 돈…
Help me pick it up. It's mine. Hurry.
내가 가져갈 수 있도록 도와주세요. 그것은 내 것입니다. 서두르다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
What?
무엇?
Hey, Hwang. It's me.
안녕, 황. 나야.
DIRECTOR YUN JAE-BEOM
Director 윤재범
FINANCIAL SUPERVISORY SERVICE, CAPITAL MARKET INVESTIGATION DIVISION
금융감독 서비스, 자본시장조사과
You're being accused of accepting bribes,
뇌물수수 혐의로 고소를 당하고 있습니다.
so you've been suspended from duty.
그래서 당신은 직무정지 처분을 받았습니다.
- Pardon? - Good luck.
- 뭐라고요? - 행운을 빌어요.
Wait, sir. Hello?
잠깐만요. 안녕하세요?
That was Director Yun, right?
윤 감독님 맞죠?
I'll say my goodbyes here.
여기서 작별 인사를 할게요.
Wait. Hold on. Hey!
기다리다. 기다리다. 여기요!
EPISODE 1: THE WOMAN KNOWN AS THE WITCH OF YEOUIDO
에피소드 1: 여의도의 마녀로 알려진 여자
HANO BANK
하노은행
JULY 3, 1997, FINANCIAL DISTRICT, YEOUIDO
1997년 7월 3일, 여의도 금융 지구
Foreign capital is exiting swiftly in the wake of the Asian financial crisis.
외국 자본이 빠르게 빠져나가고 있습니다 아시아 금융 위기의 여파.
The mounting pressure to service short-term foreign loans
장착 압력 단기 해외 대출 서비스
is further stoking anxiety in financial markets.
불안을 더욱 가중시키고 있습니다 금융 시장에서
FULL-SERVICE SHOE REPAIR
풀서비스 신발 수리
With the rising living costs,
생활비 상승으로
widespread economic difficulties are to be anticipated.
광범위한 경제적 어려움 기대됩니다.
Seongsu Bridge in Seoul reopened today,
오늘 재개통된 서울 성수대교
two years and eight months after its collapse.
2년 8개월 붕괴 후
The bridge that once took 32 innocent lives
한때 있었던 다리 32명의 무고한 생명
has risen anew as a fortified…
요새로 새롭게 떠올랐습니다...
Last…
마지막…
Give me a second.
잠시만 기다려 주세요.
Here you go.
여기요.
Three cartons of San Cigarettes, please.
산 담배 세 상자 주세요.
It's for our boss.
우리 상사를 위한 거예요.
Gosh.
이런.
I'll take a pair of tights too.
나도 스타킹 하나 가져갈게.
Oh, you can't. Those are reserved.
아, 그럴 수 없어요. 그것들은 예약되어 있습니다.
It should be first-come, first-served.
선착순이어야 합니다.
Let me have them.
나한테 갖다 줘.
HIGH ELASTICITY SMILE TIGHTS
높은 탄력성 스마일 타이츠
Sidewalks have limited space.
보도에는 공간이 제한되어 있습니다.
Maybe consider a single file instead of side-by-side.
단일 파일을 고려해 보세요. 대신 나란히.
What's her deal?
그녀의 거래는 무엇입니까?
I have two bits of good news and one bad. Pick your choice.
좋은 소식 두 가지와 나쁜 소식 하나가 있습니다. 원하는 것을 선택하세요.
Can we start with the good?
좋은 것부터 시작해볼까요?
You have been promoted
당신은 승진했습니다
to team manager at the Financial Supervisory Service,
팀 매니저에게 금융감독원에서
and confirmed probe into the slush fund of Hanmin Investment & Securities.
비자금 수사 확정 한민투자증권입니다.
I foresaw both.
나는 둘 다 예상했다.
And the bad news.
그리고 나쁜 소식.
All your team members have handed in their resignations.
모든 팀원 사직서를 제출했습니다.
They refuse to accept you as their team manager.
그들은 당신을 받아들이기를 거부합니다 팀 매니저로서.
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
사직서
You should process them.
처리해야 합니다.
Hey, kid.
안녕, 꼬마야.
They're my subordinates too. They're our family.
그 사람들도 내 부하들이야. 그들은 우리 가족이에요.
Not for me.
나를 위해서가 아닙니다.
How are we a family when we never even shared a meal?
우리는 어떻게 가족인가요? 우리가 밥도 나눠먹지 않았을 때?
CAPITAL MARKET INVESTIGATION DIVISION
자본시장 조사과
Hong Keum-bo, that ruthless brat.
홍금보, 그 무자비한 놈.
How could she stab her boss in the back to steal his job?
그녀는 어떻게 상사의 등을 찌를 수 있었습니까? 그의 직업을 훔치려고?
Listen.
듣다.
She has no sense of camaraderie or loyalty.
그녀는 감각이 없어 동지애나 충성심.
How can we serve under someone we can't trust?
우리는 어떻게 봉사할 수 있는가 믿을 수 없는 사람 밑에서?
The Witch of Yeouido is coming.
여의도의 마녀가 온다.
You should be thanking your lucky stars that you didn't go down with Hwang.
행운의 별들에게 감사해야 해요 당신이 황씨와 함께하지 않았다는 것.
It was touch-and-go for you.
그것은 당신을 위한 터치 앤 고였습니다.
TEAM MANAGER HONG KEUM-BO
팀장 홍금보
These are the resignations you've submitted.
이것들은 사임이다 당신은 제출했습니다.
I guess you were in such a rush to leave your jobs
아마 당신은 그랬을 것 같아요 직장을 그만두려고 너무 서두르다
that you completely ignored the chain of command in this organization
넌 완전히 무시했지 이 조직의 지휘계통
and went straight to the director's office.
그리고 바로 갔다 감독실로.
Complaints are not exempt from protocol.
불만 사항은 프로토콜에서 면제되지 않습니다.
You all have two options at this point.
이 시점에서는 모두 두 가지 옵션이 있습니다.
Option A.
옵션 A.
"I refuse to serve under that brat, Hong Keum-bo."
"나는 봉사를 거부한다 그 새끼 밑에, 홍금보."
"Screw this. I quit."
"이거 망쳐버려. 나 그만뒀어."
Option B.
옵션 B.
"Hong Keum-bo, that pitbull, possesses neither camaraderie nor loyalty,
"홍금보, 저 핏불, 동지애도 없고 충성심도 없다.
but I'll build myself a lasting career with her
하지만 난 나 자신을 만들 거야 그녀와의 지속적인 경력
because she's good at her job."
그 사람 일을 잘하니까."
Success requires talent, not faith.
성공하려면 믿음이 아니라 재능이 필요합니다.
We'll have a meeting in ten minutes.
우리는 10분 후에 회의를 가질 예정입니다.
Come to the meeting room
회의실로 오세요
if you wish to work with me.
나와 함께 일하고 싶다면.
Good morning.
좋은 아침이에요.
While investigating the offshore shell companies
조사하면서 역외 페이퍼컴퍼니
that diverted funds for MU Holdings' stock price manipulation,
자금을 유용한 것 MU홀딩스의 주가조작 혐의로
I uncovered a fascinating fact.
흥미로운 사실을 발견했습니다.
HANMIN CHAIRMAN KANG PIL-BEOM SUED FOR ASSAULT BY FEMALE LAWYER
한민회장 강필범 여성 변호사의 폭행 혐의로 고소당함
- There he is! - Let's go!
- 저기 있어요! - 갑시다!
Chairman Kang, how do you respond to the allegations?
강 회장님, 혐의에 대해 어떻게 대응하시나요?
Do you care to comment?
댓글을 달고 싶으신가요?
CHAIRMAN KANG PIL-BEOM HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
강필범 회장 한민투자증권
That case was already dismissed.
그 사건은 이미 기각됐어요.
Due to that assault case,
해당 폭행사건으로 인해
he handed over management rights to his only son.
그가 넘겨줬어 외아들에게 경영권을 준다.
Pildong was a new law firm that was established only last November,
필동은 새로운 법무법인이었습니다. 작년 11월에야 설립된
but they ended up representing Chairman Kang.
하지만 그들은 결국 강 회장을 대표한다.
Why?
왜?
Because its senior managing partner
고위 관리 파트너이기 때문에
worked as general counsel for Hanmin until October.
법무 자문위원으로 근무 10월까지 한민을 위해.
Subsequently, they were appointed as counsel
이어서, 그들은 변호사로 임명되었습니다
for three well-capitalized shell companies.
자본금이 넉넉한 3인용 페이퍼컴퍼니.
We also suspect Hanmin to be the source of their funds.
우리도 한민을 의심한다 자금의 원천이 됩니다.
Hey, do you think Hanmin is some ordinary corner shop?
야, 한민아 생각하니? 평범한 모퉁이 가게인가요?
You're poking a bear here.
당신은 여기서 곰을 찌르고 있습니다.
Why would I ever pursue a corner shop?
내가 왜 모퉁이 가게를 찾겠습니까?
HANMIN'S DECADE-LONG ALLEGATIONS
한민의 10년 동안의 주장
In the past decade, Hanmin, long called the heart of Yeouido,
지난 10년 동안 한민은 오랫동안 여의도의 심장이라 불렸던
has been suspected of stock price manipulation
의심되었다 주가조작의
five times.
다섯 번.
Three associates implicated in the cases died by suicide.
연루된 동료 3명 자살로 사망한 경우도 있다.
Victim count soars
피해자 수가 급증
if you include the retail investors who lost money, time, and lives.
개인투자자를 포함한다면 돈, 시간, 생명을 잃은 사람.
Slush funds estimated to have been siphoned by the chairman's family alone
비자금이 발생한 것으로 추정된다. 회장 가족들만 빨아들인다
exceed 100 billion won.
1000억원이 넘는다.
How much longer must we let this shameless looting slide?
얼마나 더 방치해야 할까요? 이 뻔뻔한 약탈 슬라이드?
It's time we do our jobs.
이제 우리가 일을 할 시간입니다.
All right?
괜찮은?
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
An internal probe into Hanmin's slush fund?
내부 프로브 한민 비자금에?
The prosecution and Financial Supervisory Service
검찰 및 금융감독원
have already formed a task force team.
이미 태스크 포스 팀을 구성했습니다.
CHIEF OF STAFF SONG JU-RAN HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
송주란 실장 한민투자증권
Thank goodness I still have junior alumni out in the field right now.
다행스럽게도 아직 후배 동창이 남아있습니다. 지금 현장에 나가 있어요.
Without me, you'd never be privy to such intel.
나 없이는 당신은 결코 그런 정보를 접할 수 없을 것입니다.
Mr. Oh.
오 씨.
I guess your alumni lacked the clout to stop it.
아무래도 당신의 동창인 것 같아요 그것을 막을 힘이 부족했다.
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OH DEOK-GYU HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
상무이사 오덕규 한민투자증권
Despite our generous yearly agency "upkeep" payoffs.
우리의 넉넉한 연간에도 불구하고 대행사의 "유지" 보상.
How could you know so little when you're the chief of staff?
어떻게 그렇게 적게 알 수 있었나요? 당신이 참모총장일 때요?
There's always that one guy looking to earn a medal wherever you go.
항상 그 사람이 있어요 어디를 가든지 메달을 따려고 합니다.
Is this news to you?
이 소식이 당신에게 있습니까?
It's just a pointless moral crusade fueled by naked ambition.
그건 무의미한 도덕적 십자군일 뿐이야 적나라한 야망에 힘입어.
And the bastard at the helm has latched onto our company,
그리고 지휘하는 놈이 우리 회사에 딱 걸렸어.
determined to drag it down.
끌어 내리기로 결심했습니다.
Can we get the task force roster?
태스크 포스 명단을 얻을 수 있나요?
Of course. You know me.
물론. 당신은 나를 알고 있습니다.
I've already acquired it. Here.
나는 이미 그것을 획득했습니다. 여기.
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES SLUSH FUND TASK FORCE
한민투자증권 비자금 태스크포스
FINANCIAL SUPERVISORY SERVICE: YUN JAE-BEOM, HONG KEUM-BO…
금융 감독 서비스: 윤재범, 홍금보…
I'll report this to the chairman myself.
제가 직접 회장님께 보고하겠습니다.
Are you suggesting I let the prosecution investigate me?
내가 허락하자고 제안하는 거야? 검찰이 나를 조사한다고?
I believe this is our last chance
이번이 마지막 기회라고 믿어
to right the wrongs we may have committed.
우리가 저지른 잘못을 바로잡기 위해.
"Our chance"?
"우리의 기회"?
Are you sure this isn't you
이 사람이 당신이 아닌 것이 확실한가요?
taking your shot to kick me out and take my place?
총을 쏘다 나를 쫓아내고 내 자리를 차지하려고?
Father.
아버지.
No one in this country would ever dare to come after me, you punk.
이 나라의 어느 누구도 감히 감히 그렇게 하지 못할 것이다. 날 따라오려고, 이 새끼야.
This is my company.
이것은 내 회사입니다.
I built it from the ground up…
기초부터 쌓았는데…
"This company does not belong to me alone."
"이 회사는 나 혼자만의 것이 아니다."
"It belongs to all of the Hanmin employees."
"에 속한다 한민 임직원 여러분."
Those were your words.
그것은 당신의 말이었습니다.
Please reconsider.
다시 생각해보세요.
Why you…
왜 당신은…
That punk.
그 새끼.
Why I ought to…
내가 그래야 하는 이유는…
Sir.
선생님.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Are you all right?
괜찮으세요?
Ms. Song.
송 씨.
Do you think Myeong-hwi…
명휘 씨 생각엔…
could switch sides on me?
내 편을 바꿀 수 있을까?
I'll keep an eye on him.
나는 그를 계속 지켜볼 것이다.
All right.
괜찮은.
You do that.
당신은 그렇게합니다.
We suspect two divisions in Hanmin,
한민 2개 부문 의심
the Trading and Research Divisions,
무역 및 연구 부문,
to have spearheaded the illicit trading.
불법거래를 주도한 셈이다.
We've confirmed that a portion of the domestically acquired slush fund
일부임을 확인했습니다. 국내에서 취득한 비자금 중
was deposited into an account
계좌로 입금되었습니다
belonging to Kang Pil-beom's only daughter, Ms. Kang Nora.
강필범 소속 외동딸 강노라 씨.
An overseas account?
해외계좌인가요?
Yes, Kang Nora is a US citizen.
네, 강노라는 미국 시민입니다.
That'll take even more time to investigate then.
그러면 시간이 더 걸릴 거예요 그때 조사하려고.
Follow the trail of money to uncover the corrupt instigator.
돈의 흔적을 따라가다 부패한 선동자를 밝혀내기 위해.
In order to secure solid evidence that can substantiate the charges--
확실한 증거 확보를 위해 혐의를 입증할 수 있는
Right, so if you really wanted to go after Hanmin,
그렇죠, 정말 원했다면 한민을 쫓아가려고
you should've called me in after securing concrete evidence.
너 나한테 전화했어야 했는데 구체적인 증거 확보 후.
Hong!
홍!
I'll be back after I secure it.
확보한 후 다시 돌아오겠습니다.
Take care, sir.
조심하세요.
Evidence!
증거!
He's so damn obnoxious.
그 사람은 정말 짜증나는 사람이에요.
That's bookworms for you.
그것은 당신을위한 책벌레입니다.
You're not any less.
당신은 그 이하도 아닙니다.
But still, without him,
하지만 그래도 그 사람이 없으면
this investigation into Hanmin would've never taken off.
한민에 대한 이번 조사 결코 이륙하지 않았을 것입니다.
That's why I'm biting my tongue.
그래서 혀를 깨물고 있습니다.
What's with the attitude?
태도는 어떻습니까?
Then again, you got solid grades too.
그리고 또, 당신도 좋은 성적을 받았어요.
Let's hurry up. The president is waiting for us.
서두르자. 대통령께서 우리를 기다리고 계십니다.
It's not like he's waiting out in the hot sun.
그 사람이 밖에서 기다리고 있는 것 같지는 않아 뜨거운 태양 속에서.
GENERAL MANAGER SO GYEONG-DONG TRADING DIVISION, HANMIN
소경동 과장 한민 무역사업부
MANAGER BANG JIN-MOK RISK MANAGEMENT DIVISION, HANMIN
방진목 매니저 한민 리스크관리본부
GENERAL MANAGER CHA JUNG-IL RESEARCH DIVISION, HANMIN
차정일 실장 한민 연구본부
He's comfortably waiting for us in his office.
그 사람은 편안하게 우리를 기다리고 있어요 그의 사무실에서.
Hey, Bang.
안녕, 뱅.
At least tuck that darn shirt in, will you?
최소한 그 셔츠는 집어넣으세요. 당신은?
Mind your potbelly first.
먼저 배를 조심하세요.
Big Al should be at this thing, not me.
이 일에는 내가 아니라 Big Al이 있어야 합니다.
What does he know?
그는 무엇을 알고 있나요?
The fact that we three were called means it's an emergency.
우리 셋이 불렸다는 사실 긴급상황이라는 뜻이다.
- Let's go already. - Come on.
- 벌써 가자. - 어서 해봐요.
We hear a full-scale investigation into both breach of fiduciary duty
본격적인 조사를 듣습니다 두 가지 모두 수탁의무 위반
and illicit trading is underway.
불법 거래가 진행되고 있습니다.
We'll respond accordingly,
그에 맞춰 답변해드리겠습니다,
but since Trading and Research are core divisions,
하지만 무역 및 연구 이후 핵심 부서이며,
you will need to prepare further independently.
당신은해야 할 것입니다 더 독립적으로 준비하십시오.
Understood.
이해했다.
Will do.
그럴 것이다.
Is there actually a slush fund?
실제로 비자금이 존재하는 걸까요?
Even if there is one…
하나라도 있다고 해도…
we must make it not exist.
우리는 그것이 존재하지 않도록 만들어야 합니다.
First, I'd like to ask Risk Management
먼저 리스크 관리에 대해 묻고 싶습니다.
to look into the task force members.
태스크 포스 구성원을 조사합니다.
As in dig for dirt?
흙을 파는 것처럼?
Whatever comes up.
무슨 일이 일어나든.
Find out as much as you can.
가능한 한 많이 알아보세요.
FINANCIAL SUPERVISORY SERVICE
금융 감독 서비스
ACCESS TO HANMIN IS REQUIRED TO INVESTIGATE OVERSEAS ACCOUNTS
한민에 대한 액세스가 필요합니다 해외계좌 조사
HANMIN SLUSH FUND INVESTIGATION SECOND MEETING REPORT
한민 비자금 조사 두 번째 회의 보고서
Nam Dong-gi, did that fax come in?
남동기 씨, 그 팩스가 들어왔나요?
Cheers!
건배!
- Cheers!
- 건배!
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
NEW MAIL FROM YEHPPEE@KEBEO.CO.KR
YEHPPEE@KEBEO.CO.KR에서 보낸 새 메일
"Yehppee"?
"응피"?
TIP: REGARDING HANMIN'S SLUSH FUND
TIP: 한민 비자금 관련
I have the accounting ledger that proves the Kang family's corruption.
회계원장이 있습니다 강씨 일가의 비리를 입증하는 것입니다.
Let's talk in person.
직접 이야기해보자.
Are you Yehppee?
당신은 Yehppee입니까?
No.
아니요.
Inspector Hong?
홍 검사님?
President Kang,
강 대표님,
plea bargaining should be done with the prosecution.
항변교섭을 해야 한다 검찰이랑.
Guilt needs to be proven before any bargaining, no?
죄책감은 입증되어야 한다 협상하기 전에요, 그렇죠?
You've got a long way to go.
갈 길이 멀다.
Oh, I get it.
아, 알겠습니다.
Is there a box of cash in your trunk?
트렁크에 현금 상자가 있나요?
Overflowing with fresh and green bills?
신선하고 녹색 지폐가 넘쳐나요?
I have something even better.
나에겐 더 좋은 것이 있다.
How about the slush fund ledger?
비자금 장부는 어떻습니까?
The slush fund ledger?
비자금 장부요?
Why aren't you answering it?
왜 대답하지 않습니까?
That will be my assistant calling.
그건 내 비서가 전화할 거야.
My assistant is always by my side, fully aware of what I do and whom I meet.
내 조수는 항상 내 옆에 있고, 내가 무엇을 하는지, 누구를 만나는지 잘 알고 있습니다.
But I left today without saying anything.
그런데 오늘 아무 말도 없이 떠났어요.
I wanted to see
보고 싶었어요
if you were someone who could be entrusted with a life…
당신이 누군가였다면 생명을 맡길 수 있는 사람...
for myself.
나 자신을 위해.
Whose life?
누구의 삶?
Chairman Kang Pil-beom's?
강필범 회장?
Or yours?
아니면 당신 것입니까?
I'm talking about Hanmin's.
한민의 얘기다.
You could end up receiving a prison sentence.
결국 받게 될 수도 있습니다 징역형.
Yes. I'm prepared for as much.
예. 그만큼 준비가 되어 있어요.
"Follow the trail of money to uncover the corrupt instigator."
"돈의 흔적을 따라가라 부패한 선동자를 밝히기 위해."
Those were your words.
그것은 당신의 말이었습니다.
Follow the trail of money to uncover the corrupt instigator.
돈의 흔적을 따라가다 부패한 선동자를 밝혀내기 위해.
Do we have a damn rat?
빌어먹을 쥐가 있나요?
If they're not stopped now, they'll siphon off the money
지금 멈추지 않는다면, 그 사람들은 돈을 빨아먹을 거야
even more carefully and systematically.
더욱 세심하고 체계적으로
To prevent that from happening, Yehppee and I
그런 일이 일어나지 않도록, 예피와 나
are getting the ledger together for whistleblowing purposes.
장부를 정리하고 있습니다 내부고발 목적
I believe this will be…
나는 이것이 될 것이라고 믿는다…
our last chance
우리의 마지막 기회
to flip the tables.
테이블을 뒤집으려고.
If you're messing with me,
나한테 장난치는 거라면,
or if you ever betray me in the future,
아니면 앞으로 나를 배신한다면,
you and I will both be swimming with the fishes in the Han River.
너와 나 둘 다 그럴 거야 한강에서 물고기들과 함께 수영해요.
I plan to live
나는 살 계획이다
a long, honest life with integrity.
성실하고 길고 정직한 삶.
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
Consider it a welcome gift.
환영 선물이라고 생각하세요.
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
After you requested solid evidence that outlines the flow of funds,
확실한 증거를 요청하신 후 자금의 흐름을 간략히 설명하는 것입니다.
I was able to confirm a few details of the funds Hanmin leaked abroad.
몇 가지 사항을 확인할 수 있었습니다 한민의 해외 유출자금 중
You're quick.
당신은 빠릅니다.
You asked for evidence, didn't you, sir?
증거를 요구하셨죠, 그렇죠?
We'd like to request
우리는 요청하고 싶습니다
a search and seizure warrant based on evidence of funds diverted
수색 및 압수 영장 전용된 자금의 증거에 기초하여
to Ms. Kang Nora's personal account and offshore corporations.
강노라씨 개인 계정으로 그리고 해외 기업.
Yes, all right.
응, 알았어.
FOREIGN EXCHANGE RECEIPT
외환영수증
Once the warrant is issued, the prosecution will search and seize
영장이 발부되면 검찰이 압수수색할 예정이다
tomorrow morning.
내일 아침
Let's meet up at our spot tonight.
오늘 밤 우리 자리에서 만나자.
All right.
괜찮은.
Multivitamin, amino acids, and deer antler extract, sir.
종합비타민, 아미노산, 그리고 녹용추출물도요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I sometimes think about
나는 가끔 생각한다.
what would've happened if I had finished med school.
무슨 일이 일어났을까 내가 의과대학을 졸업했다면.
The chairman would've bought a hospital.
회장님은 병원을 사셨을 겁니다.
I wouldn't have been a good doctor.
나는 좋은 의사가 되지 못했을 것이다.
I heard you were picked as the Outstanding Woman Employee.
네가 뽑혔다고 들었어 뛰어난 여성 직원으로.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
It's a cash bonus.
현금 보너스입니다.
Oh my.
아, 이런.
You did manage to become a good boss.
당신은 좋은 상사가 되었습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I think President Kang has a woman.
강 대표에게 여자가 있는 것 같다.
Who?
WHO?
I'm not sure, but he's been seeing her regularly.
잘 모르겠습니다. 하지만 그는 정기적으로 그녀를 만나고 있어요.
I heard him setting up a date for tonight.
그 사람이 오늘 밤 데이트 약속을 잡는 걸 들었어요.
All right.
괜찮은.
You can pick up the slush fund ledger
비자금 원장을 수령하실 수 있습니다.
at the president's office on the 12th floor
대통령 집무실에서 12층에
in Hanmin's head office.
한민 본사에서
It's being delivered as we speak.
우리가 말하는 대로 전달되고 있습니다.
JULY, 1997
1997년 7월
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
PRESIDENT KANG MYEONG-HWI
강명휘 회장
WEEKLY TRADING RISK SUMMARY REPORT
주간 거래 위험 요약 보고서
You're listening to Sunrise Radio Show. The time is now 5 a.m.
선라이즈 라디오 쇼를 듣고 계십니다. 지금 시간은 오전 5시입니다.
The first song I'll play for you today
오늘 제가 여러분을 위해 연주할 첫 번째 노래
is from the soundtrack for the film, Beat.
영화 Beat의 사운드트랙입니다.
Here's Im Chang-jung's "Woeful Ballad."
임창정의 '비애 발라드'를 감상해 보세요.
- Hey, son. - Hey!
- 안녕, 아들아. - 여기요!
I knew you'd show up in this dismal state.
나는 당신이 이런 암울한 상태로 나타날 줄 알았습니다.
Good morning to you, too, Dad.
아빠도 좋은 아침이에요.
You weren't drinking all night, right?
밤새도록 술을 마시진 않았지, 그렇지?
I didn't drink at all.
나는 전혀 술을 마시지 않았습니다.
I saw three late-night movies in Jongno.
종로에서 심야영화 세 편을 봤다.
Change before you go up to see the chairman. Now.
올라가기 전에 갈아입으세요 회장님을 만나러. 지금.
What's with this emergency meeting?
이번 긴급회의는 어떻게 됐나요?
Are all the geezers here already?
괴짜들 벌써 다 왔나요?
Why you…
왜 당신은…
Take care of that for me.
그건 나를 위해 처리해 주세요.
I'm worried he's too good-looking, just like me.
너무 잘생겨서 걱정인데 나처럼.
Put your game away.
게임을 치워두세요.
Read the room. The chairman is coming!
방을 읽어보세요. 회장님 오십니다!
Don't you all have brains between those ears?
다들 뇌가 없나? 그 귀 사이?
Are your hands and feet just for show?
당신의 손과 발은 단지 보여주기 위한 것입니까?
How could I have been informed
내가 어떻게 알 수 있었을까?
of the prosecution's search and seizure
검찰의 압수수색에 대해
just three hours before it's supposed to happen?
딱 3시간만 그 일이 일어나기 전에?
I actually acquired intel that the prosecution
실제로 인텔을 획득했습니다 그 검찰은
was carrying out a probe a few days ago.
며칠 전에 조사를 진행하고 있었어요.
And?
그리고?
President Kang said he wanted to tell you himself.
강 대표는 이렇게 말했다. 그는 당신에게 직접 말하고 싶었습니다.
He insisted.
그는 주장했다.
What did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
Myeong-hwi knew about this?
명휘도 이 사실을 알고 있었나요?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Where is he right now?
그는 지금 어디에 있나요?
Well, I…
글쎄, 난…
I'll give him a call, Grandfather.
제가 전화할게요, 할아버지.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
What?
무엇?
The police?
경찰?
The deceased victim
사망한 피해자
in the traffic accident that occurred at 6 a.m. today in Mapo-gu
발생한 교통사고 오늘 오전 6시 마포구
was identified as Hanmin President Kang Myeong-hwi,
다음으로 식별되었습니다 한민회장 강명휘
who was under investigation for fiduciary breach and embezzlement.
조사를 받고 있던 사람 신탁 위반 및 횡령
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES PRESIDENT KANG MYEONG-HWI KILLED IN TRAFFIC ACCIDENT
한민투자증권 사장 강명휘 교통사고로 사망
You should've told me that sooner, you punk.
그건 좀 더 일찍 나한테 말했어야 했는데, 너 펑크.
I wanted to secure the evidence first.
증거를 먼저 확보하고 싶었다.
He told me he'd leave the slush fund ledger
그 사람이 나한테 떠날 거라고 했어 비자금 장부
in his office on the 12th floor.
12층에 있는 그의 사무실에서요.
We just need to get it during today's search and seizure--
우리는 그것을 얻기만 하면 된다 오늘 수색 및 압수 과정에서
Seriously?
진심으로요?
You expect me to proceed with that search?
내가 그 수색을 계속할 거라고 생각하시나요?
The only son of the great Chairman Kang is dead!
외아들 위대한 강회장님이 돌아가셨습니다!
I'm also upset about President Kang's accident,
나도 속상해 강 회장의 사고에 대해
but we need to retrieve the slush fund ledger.
하지만 우리는 검색해야 해 비자금 장부.
QUARTERLY BUSINESS PLAN
분기별 사업 계획
Did you find it?
찾았나요?
What's wrong? Is it not there?
무슨 일이야? 거기 없나요?
This can't be.
이럴 수는 없습니다.
MEETING ROOM
회의실
The investigation's suspended?
수사가 중단됐나요?
The press has turned on us after President Kang's death.
언론이 우리에게 등을 돌렸어요 강회장 사망 이후.
They're even saying the pressure from the investigation led him to suicide.
압력이 가해진다고도 하던데 조사 결과 그를 자살로 이끌었습니다.
It wasn't suicide. If anything, homicide--
자살은 아니었습니다. 살인이라면--
You're in no place to make such calls.
당신은 그런 전화를 걸 수 있는 곳이 아닙니다.
What if it wasn't an accident?
사고가 아니었다면?
What if Chairman Kang stepped in after he discovered
강 회장이 끼어든다면? 그가 발견한 후
that President Kang had decided to join forces with us?
그 강 회장은 우리와 힘을 합치기로 결정했나요?
- Hey. - What's this now?
- 여기요. - 지금 이게 뭐야?
Who did he join forces with?
그는 누구와 힘을 합쳤습니까?
Our Inspector Hong Keum-bo
우리 홍금보 경위님
had been covertly colluding with President Kang.
은밀히 공모하고 있었다 강 회장과 함께.
They'd sort of become acquaintances…
그들은 일종의 지인이 될 것입니다…
What are you…
당신은 무엇입니까…
Director Yun just found this out.
윤 감독이 그걸 알아낸 거죠.
You should tell them yourself, Ms. Hong.
홍씨가 직접 말해야 해요.
Shut up.
입 다물어.
It appears…
그것은 나타납니다…
you need to explain yourself,
스스로 설명해야 하고,
Inspector Hong Keum-bo.
홍금보 경감.
SENT
보냄
SUBJECT: YEHPPEE, THIS IS HONG KEUM-BO STATUS: UNREAD
제목: 예삐, 홍금보입니다 상태: 읽지 않음
COMPOSE
작성
HELLO, YEHPPEE. THIS IS HONG KEUM-BO.
안녕하세요, 예피입니다. 홍금보입니다.
HEARING ABOUT PRESIDENT KANG'S DEATH MUST HAVE BEEN UPSETTING.
강 회장의 부고 소식을 듣다 분명 속상했을 거예요.
REGARDING THE SLUSH FUND LEDGER…
비자금 원장에 관하여…
NOTICE OF APPOINTMENT
임명 통지
NAM DONG-GI PROMOTED TO TEAM MANAGER, GRADE 4
남동기 4급 팀 매니저로 승진
NOTICE OF DISCIPLINARY ACTION
징계 조치 통지
HONG KEUM-BO: THREE-MONTH PAY CUT STANDBY ASSIGNMENT
홍금보 : 3개월 급여 삭감 대기 할당
CAUSE: VIOLATION OF REPORTING OBLIGATIONS
원인: 보고 의무 위반
Good work!
잘했어요!
Congratulations!
축하해요!
- Team! - Manager!
- 팀! - 관리자!
- Sir! - Why, thank you, everyone.
- 선생님! - 다들 고마워요.
Let our camaraderie never die.
우리의 동지애가 절대 죽지 않게 해주세요.
But how could I possibly move in when the garbage truck hasn't left yet?
그런데 내가 어떻게 이사할 수 있겠어? 쓰레기차가 아직 떠나지 않았을 때?
- Team Manager Nam! - Sir!
- 남팀장님! - 선생님!
Sure. Thanks.
확신하는. 감사해요.
Mom…
엄마…
ULLALA CHICKEN
울랄라치킨
A bottle of soju, please.
소주 한 병 주세요.
Can't you see we're busy?
우리 바쁜 거 안 보여?
You can't be a spinster who just sits on her ass all day.
넌 노처녀가 될 수 없어 하루종일 엉덩이 위에 앉아 있는 사람.
Honey, I think I need a new motorcycle.
여보, 새 오토바이가 필요한 것 같아요.
Hey, it's been a while.
안녕하세요, 오랜만이에요.
Why, it's my dearest daughter.
뭐, 내 가장 사랑하는 딸이니까.
Everyone, let me introduce you to her.
여러분, 그녀를 소개하겠습니다.
She's my eldest who works in a fancy office in Seoul.
그 사람은 내 장남이야 서울의 멋진 사무실에서 일하는 사람.
Wow, look at you drinking soju straight.
와, 소주 똑바로 마시는 것 좀 보세요.
So cool.
정말 멋지다.
Here.
여기.
Mom, should I just quit my job?
엄마, 저 그냥 회사 그만둘까요?
That's an excellent idea.
정말 좋은 생각이에요.
You've been a career woman long enough. It's time to get married.
당신은 충분히 오랫동안 커리어 우먼으로 살아왔습니다. 이제 결혼할 시간이에요.
The blind date you ruthlessly turned down last year
소개팅 넌 작년에 무자비하게 거절했지
just had a baby boy.
방금 아들을 낳았어요.
Apparently, people call that a "honeymoon baby."
아무래도 사람들이 그렇게 부르나 보다. "허니문 베이비".
If you'd just been a bit nicer to him, that would've been your baby.
그 사람에게 조금만 더 친절하게 대해줬더라면, 그 사람은 당신의 아기였을 거예요.
That's just your wishful thinking.
그것은 단지 당신의 희망사항일 뿐입니다.
…and the slush fund investigation has come to a halt.
…그리고 비자금 조사 정지되었습니다.
The arrest warrant for Chairman Kang Pil-beom
체포 영장 강필범 회장님께
has been dismissed.
해산되었습니다.
Citing insufficient evidence, prosecutors decided not to indict on allegations
증거불충분, 검찰 주장 혐의에 대해 기소하지 않기로 결정
that hundreds of billions of won had been diverted into an illegal slush fund.
수천억 원이 있었다 불법 비자금으로 전용되었습니다.
On July 22nd, the legal community weighed in,
7월 22일 법조계가 참여했습니다.
stating that the prosecution
검찰은
must have arrived at this decision due to insufficient discovery
이러한 결정에 도달했음에 틀림없습니다 발견 부족으로 인해
after their search and seizure…
수색 및 압수 이후...
It's not too late.
너무 늦지 않았습니다.
Anything's possible between a man and a woman.
무엇이든 가능하다 남자와 여자 사이.
Just start dating. You need to start to progress.
그냥 데이트를 시작하세요. 발전을 시작해야합니다.
We actually just received another blind date offer.
우리는 실제로 방금 받았습니다. 또 다른 소개팅 제안.
The deaconess's paternal cousin's daughter-in-law's
집사님의 사촌동생 며느리의
maternal cousin's brother.
외삼촌의 동생.
- It's too good to pass up. - Yes.
- 그냥 지나치기엔 너무 아까워요. - 예.
Let's proceed. Set a date.
계속합시다. 날짜를 정하세요.
I should get going.
나는 가야한다.
Hold on. Take this with you.
기다리다. 이것을 가지고 가십시오.
This is kimchi,
이건 김치,
and this is boiled chicken.
그리고 이건 삶은 닭고기예요.
The weather's warm, so put it straight in the fridge.
날씨가 따뜻해요, 그러니 바로 냉장고에 넣어두세요.
I didn't bring my car.
나는 차를 가져오지 않았다.
Beyond the Han River, to the World! To the Future!
한강을 넘어 세계로! 미래로!
That's a talisman for attracting men.
남자를 유혹하는 부적이죠.
I had to fry ten extra chickens to pay for this.
닭 10마리를 더 튀겨야 했어 이것에 대한 비용을 지불합니다.
Do you really think that would work?
정말 그게 효과가 있을 거라고 생각하시나요?
Would you really want a son-in-law who was drawn to me not out of love,
정말 사위를 원하시나요? 사랑해서가 아니라 나에게 끌린 사람,
but only because of that talisman?
하지만 그 부적 때문에?
You think I want to do this?
내가 이걸 하고 싶어할 것 같아?
Your married friends already have kids in school.
결혼한 친구들 이미 학교에 다니는 아이들이 있어요.
Mom, I have no friends.
엄마, 저는 친구가 없어요.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
It attracts men. You want me to carry it around?
그것은 남자들을 매료시킵니다. 내가 그걸 가지고 다니기를 원하시나요?
Why would I carry it around? I have no need for it at all.
내가 왜 그것을 가지고 다니겠습니까? 나는 그것이 전혀 필요하지 않습니다.
HANMIN IS LOOKING FOR ASPIRING TALENT
한민은 인재를 찾고 있습니다
Jeez, my mom's really something else.
이런, 우리 엄마는 정말 다른 사람이야.
Hey!
여기요!
You damn punks!
빌어먹을 놈들아!
Damn it!
젠장!
Did you just get mugged?
방금 강도를 당했나요?
Yes.
예.
- Get in. - Thank you.
- 들어가세요. - 고마워요.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Hurry up and get in.
서둘러 들어가세요.
You can go. I'm fine.
가셔도 됩니다. 잘 지내요.
Damn it.
젠장.
This is why
이것이 바로 이유이다
you should know your place and not act up.
당신은 당신의 위치를 ​​알고 행동하지 않아야합니다.
You know?
알잖아?
You little…
너 좀…
- Come here. - You're dead.
- 이리 오세요. - 넌 죽었어.
The late Brother Peter Kang Myeong-hwi,
故 강명휘 베드로 형제
a servant of the Lord who became one with God,
주님의 종 하나님과 하나가 된 사람,
strove to live out the Word of God as taught in Sacred Scripture.
하나님의 말씀대로 살려고 노력했습니다. 성경에서 가르친대로.
Let us pray for our brother Peter,
우리 형제 베드로를 위해 기도합시다.
who, having been called home by the Lord,
그는 주님의 부르심을 받아 집으로 돌아왔습니다.
departed from the side of his loved ones at his young age.
사랑하는 사람의 곁을 떠났습니다 어린 나이에.
May our brother Peter, and all the faithful departed,
우리 형제 피터가 그리고 모든 충실한 사람들이 떠났습니다.
through the mercy of God, come to rest in the peace of eternal life.
하나님의 자비를 통하여, 영원한 생명의 평화 속에 안식을 누리십시오.
Amen.
아멘.
- Amen. - Amen!
- 아멘. - 아멘!
What's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
- Damn, that startled me. - Sit.
- 젠장, 깜짝 놀랐어요. - 앉다.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
- I'm sorry. - Sit down.
- 죄송합니다. - 앉으세요.
I thought today was just for family.
오늘은 가족만을 위한 날인 줄 알았는데.
MADAM CHOI IN-JA CHAIRMAN KANG PIL-BEOM'S EX-WIFE
최인자 마담 강필범 회장의 전처
Is this any place
여기가 어딘가요?
for the chairman's ex-wife, who divorced him 20 years ago, to be?
회장의 전 부인을 위해 20년 전에 그와 이혼한 사람은 누구일까요?
I do wonder.
정말 궁금합니다.
We still have our Nora.
우리에겐 아직 노라(Nora)가 있습니다.
I had to be here as her mother.
나는 그녀의 어머니로서 여기에 있어야만 했습니다.
After all, our Nora
결국 우리 노라
is the chairman's only child now.
지금은 회장의 외동아들이에요.
You were kicked out of here ages ago.
당신은 오래 전에 여기서 쫓겨났습니다.
I was never kicked out. I walked out on my own.
저는 쫓겨난 적이 없습니다. 나는 스스로 나갔다.
Albert's mother passed forever ago.
Albert의 어머니는 오래 전에 세상을 떠났습니다.
Yet here you are, still pathetically leeching off your in-law.
그런데 당신은 여전히 한심해요 당신의 시어머니를 거머리.
You dare raise your voices in my house?
감히 우리 집에서 목소리를 높여?
Sit.
앉다.
If Nora survives
노라가 살아남는다면
the three-month probationary period
3개월의 수습 기간
and becomes a full-time employee at Hanmin Investment & Securities,
그리고 정규직이 됩니다 한민투자증권에서
then I'll let you inherit the shares of the company
그럼 너한테 물려줄게 회사의 주식
that I intended to pass down to Myeong-hwi.
내가 물려주려고 했던 것 명휘에게.
My goodness. Nora.
이럴 수가. 노라.
But, sir.
하지만 선생님.
Nora didn't even major in business.
노라는 사업을 전공하지도 않았습니다.
But Albert, who studied business and did nothing else,
하지만 경영학을 전공한 알버트는 그리고 다른 건 아무것도 안 했고,
works at the company too.
회사에서도 일해요.
Didn't you drop out before you even got that degree?
탈락한 거 아냐? 학위를 받기도 전에요?
Yes.
예.
- See? - Come on now.
- 보다? - 이제 어서요.
Nora.
노라.
When you were little,
당신이 어렸을 때,
your mother paraded you around, and everyone knew your face.
네 엄마가 너를 데리고 여기저기 행진을 했고, 그리고 모두가 당신의 얼굴을 알고 있었어요.
But the only ones who know what you look like now
하지만 유일한 사람들은 지금 네가 어떻게 생겼는지 누가 알겠어?
are in this room.
이 방에 있어요.
Thus,
따라서,
you must not let on that you're my daughter.
너는 그렇게 해서는 안 된다 네가 내 딸이라는 걸.
And follow Ms. Song's guidance
그리고 송 선생님의 지시를 따르세요.
to prepare for your next step, all right?
다음 단계를 준비하기 위해서죠, 그렇죠?
We're done here.
이제 끝났습니다.
Wait, sir.
잠깐만요.
I implore you to reconsider.
다시 한번 생각해 보시길 바랍니다.
You do not get a say!
당신은 말할 것도 없습니다!
You just focus on preparing for the press conference.
준비에만 집중하세요 기자회견을 위해.
Nora, this worked out so well.
노라, 정말 잘 됐어요.
Congratulations on your new job, Auntie.
새 일을 축하해요, 이모님.
- Good luck. - Thanks.
- 행운을 빌어요. - 감사해요.
Mom, I can't do it.
엄마, 난 할 수 없어요.
I don't want to work there.
나는 그곳에서 일하고 싶지 않습니다.
Send me back to America.
저를 미국으로 다시 보내주세요.
Be quiet.
조용히 하세요.
You said you wanted to spend your life
당신은 평생을 보내고 싶다고 말했어요
burning through the money your father never spent on you.
돈을 불태우다 네 아버지는 너한테 돈을 쓴 적이 없어.
If you give up and surrender now,
지금 포기하고 굴복한다면,
Albert will take this house, the company, and everything else. Got it?
알버트가 이 집을 차지할 거예요. 회사, 그 밖의 모든 것. 알았어요?
HOSPITAL
병원
PLASTER ROOM
석고실
Damn, seriously?
젠장, 진심으로?
Keum-bo!
금보!
Hold on.
기다리다.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Have I been admitted?
나 합격했나요?
WISHING YOU A SPEEDY RECOVERY GET BETTER SOON
빠른 회복을 기원합니다 빨리 나아지세요
Maybe someone at Hanmin
어쩌면 한민에 누군가
found out about you and President Kang?
당신과 강 대표에 대해 알아냈나요?
That asshole prosecutor was attacked last night.
그 멍청한 검사 어젯밤에 공격을 받았습니다.
He has a 12-week recovery ahead of him.
그는 앞으로 12주간의 회복 기간을 갖고 있다.
This is undoubtedly a warning.
이것은 의심할 여지 없이 경고이다.
They're saying they'll come after you if you go after them.
그 사람들이 당신을 잡으러 올 거라고 하더군요 당신이 그들을 쫓아 가면.
But you know,
하지만 아시다시피,
they must be doing this because there's something to hide.
그 사람들은 분명 이런 짓을 하고 있을 거야 숨길 게 있으니까요.
What exactly are you trying to say?
정확히 무엇을 말하려는 건가요?
What if we go in person
우리가 직접 가면 어떡하지?
to retrieve the slush fund ledger?
비자금 원장을 되찾으려면?
Who? How in the world would we do that?
WHO? 세상에서 어떻게 그렇게 할 수 있을까요?
Look at the state I'm in right now.
지금 내가 어떤 상태인지 보세요.
BEYOND THE HAN RIVER, TO THE WORLD! TO THE FUTURE!
한강을 넘어 세계로! 미래로!
HANMIN AWAITS MOTIVATIONAL HIGH SCHOOL GRADUATES
한민이 기다립니다 동기 부여 고등학교 졸업생
We'll keep it a secret from the office.
사무실에는 비밀로 하겠습니다.
It'll be a secret operation with just you and me.
비밀 작전이겠지 너랑 나랑만.
You can't see what's right under your nose.
당신은 볼 수 없습니다 코 밑에 뭐가 있지?
They wouldn't imagine you doing this in their wildest dreams.
그 사람들은 네가 이런 짓을 할 거라고는 상상도 못 할 거야 그들의 가장 거친 꿈 속에서.
I won't be under their noses. I'll be stuck in a death trap.
나는 그들의 코 밑에 있지 않을 것입니다. 죽음의 덫에 걸리게 됩니다.
Do you really think President Kang died in a car accident?
강 대표님은 정말로 그렇게 생각하시나요? 교통사고로 죽었어?
Also, I'm a well-educated woman.
게다가 저는 교육을 잘 받은 여성이에요.
I'm a career woman with ten years of experience in Yeouido!
저는 10년차 커리어우먼이에요 여의도에서의 경험!
And you want me to go undercover
그리고 당신은 내가 비밀리에 가길 원해요
as some entry-level minion?
초급 미니언으로요?
- Damn it! - But I like the plan…
- 젠장! - 하지만 그 계획은 마음에 드는데…
Wait. Hold on, Hong.
잠깐만요. 잠깐만요, 홍.
Hong! Stop!
홍! 멈추다!
Hong! Come on! Wait!
홍! 어서 해봐요! 기다리다!
Hong!
홍!
BEYOND THE HAN RIVER, TO THE WORLD! TO THE FUTURE!
한강을 넘어 세계로! 미래로!
STAFF RECRUITMENT
직원 모집
ONCE IN A LIFETIME CHANCE! HANMIN IS HIRING
평생 단 한번뿐인 기회! 한민이 채용 중입니다
Take it easy.
진정하세요.
I'll take care of everything.
내가 다 알아서 할게.
Where did she go?
그녀는 어디로 갔나요?
Jeez, where the hell did she go?
이런, 대체 그녀는 어디로 간 걸까?
Director Yun!
윤 감독님!
All right, sorry. I was shortsighted.
알았어, 미안해. 나는 근시안적이었습니다.
Of course, this wouldn't work.
물론 이것은 작동하지 않습니다.
I mean, you're 35.
내 말은, 당신은 35세라는 거죠.
Who would ever think you're in your twenties?
누가 생각이나 하겠는가 당신은 20대입니까?
Maybe a mom of a 20-year-old.
아마도 20대 엄마일 겁니다.
Sir.
선생님.
For the record, everyone says I look young for my age.
기록을 위해, 다들 내가 나이에 비해 젊어 보인다고 해요.
Everyone thinks I'm in my twenties. They're so shocked when they hear my age.
다들 나를 20대라고 생각한다. 그들은 내 나이를 듣고 너무 충격을 받았습니다.
Why am I explaining myself?
내가 왜 설명하고 있는 걸까?
So?
그래서?
Are you saying you'll give it serious consideration?
당신은 말하고 있습니까? 진지하게 고려해보실 건가요?
No.
아니요.
If you want it so badly, do it yourself.
그렇게까지 원하시면 직접 하세요.
What's this?
이게 뭐야?
I'M TAKING PTO
저는 PTO를 택하고 있어요
Wait, hold on. Hong Keum-bo!
잠깐, 잠깐만요. 홍금보님!
CHAIRMAN KANG PIL-BEOM'S NATIONAL PRESS CONFERENCE
강필범 회장의 전국 기자 회견
I devoted my entire life
나는 평생을 바쳤습니다.
to serving the national economy and improving the lives
국가 경제에 봉사하기 위해 삶을 개선하고
of the people.
사람들의.
There may have been mistakes,
실수가 있었을 수도 있습니다.
but there was no illegality.
하지만 불법은 없었습니다.
At this moment,
지금 이 순간
I'm just a man
저는 그냥 남자입니다
who lost his one and only son
하나뿐인 아들을 잃은
and failed as a father.
아버지로서 실패했습니다.
BREAKING NEWS: HANMIN CHAIRMAN KANG APOLOGIZES TO THE NATION
속보: 강한민 회장 국민에게 사과하다
Even nine years ago,
9년 전만 해도,
nefarious forces slandered and attacked
사악한 세력이 비방하고 공격했습니다.
Hanmin Investment & Securities.
한민투자증권
However, it was all a lie.
그러나 그것은 모두 거짓말이었다.
And again, this time,
그리고 이번에도
I, Kang Pil-beom,
나, 강필범
will not settle.
해결되지 않습니다.
Hanmin Investment & Securities is a VIP client at our accounting firm.
한민투자증권 우리 회계법인의 VIP 고객입니다.
- Please take good care of us. - Thank you.
- 우리를 잘 보살펴 주세요. - 감사합니다.
…committed suicide by jumping from his apartment building.
…자살 아파트 건물에서 뛰어내려
She reported Hanmin for accounting fraud,
한민을 분식회계 혐의로 신고했고,
but their countersuit ruined her.
그러나 그들의 반소는 그녀를 망쳤습니다.
I will continue to
나는 계속할 것이다
stand firm against schemes, fabrications, and betrayal.
계략에 맞서 굳건히 맞서고, 조작, 그리고 배신.
I will carry on Kang Myeong-hwi's legacy
강명휘의 유산을 이어가겠습니다
with unwavering determination
흔들리지 않는 결심으로
to bring forth a new Hanmin Investment & Securities
출산 새로운 한민투자증권
that will be worthy of the Republic of Korea's stature.
그건 그럴 만한 가치가 있을 거야 대한민국의 위상이다.
FRAUD AND SLUSH FUND CHARGES ARE BASELESS!
사기 및 비자금 청구는 근거가 없습니다!
KANG, THE "PHOENIX OF YEOUIDO," PREPARES A COMEBACK
'여의도의 봉황' 강씨 컴백을 준비하다
I'll proceed with the Hanmin undercover investigation.
계속하겠습니다 한민의 잠복수사와 함께.
You've been informed.
당신은 정보를 받았습니다.
My goodness.
이럴 수가.
You refused to even budge when I begged you.
넌 꿈쩍도 거부했지 내가 당신에게 간청했을 때.
Now that it's a hot mess, you want to go?
이제 난장판이 됐으니, 갈래?
That ship has sailed.
그 배는 항해했습니다.
It's all over.
모든 것이 끝났습니다.
And they concluded the investigation into President Kang's car accident.
그리고 수사를 마쳤다. 강회장의 교통사고.
But that was no accident.
그러나 그것은 우연이 아니었습니다.
If I'm being honest, I didn't trust him 100%.
솔직하게 말하면, 나는 그를 100% 믿지 않았습니다.
I only realized he was being genuine
나는 그 사람이 진심이라는 것을 그제서야 깨달았다.
after he died and Yehppee went into hiding.
그가 죽은 후에 그리고 Yehppee는 숨어들어갔습니다.
You saw Chairman Kang's press conference, right?
강회장님 보셨죠? 기자회견, 그렇죠?
Even nine years ago,
9년 전만 해도,
nefarious forces slandered and attacked
사악한 세력이 비방하고 공격했습니다.
Hanmin Investment & Securities.
한민투자증권.
However, it was all a lie.
그러나 그것은 모두 거짓말이었습니다.
What happened nine years ago can't happen again.
9년 전에 무슨 일이 일어났나요? 다시는 일어날 수 없습니다.
I'll find Yehppee within three months…
3개월 안에 예피를 찾을게요…
and retrieve the slush fund ledger.
비자금 원장을 검색하세요.
All documents once submitted to President Kang
모든 서류 일단 강 회장에게 제출
have been shredded.
파쇄되었습니다.
And the police have quietly concluded
그리고 경찰은 조용히 결론을 내렸습니다.
his traffic accident investigation.
그의 교통사고 조사.
Now,
지금,
who knows about the slush fund details
비자금 내역 아는 사람
and the hidden cache?
숨겨진 캐시는요?
Only you…
너만…
and me, sir.
그리고 저도요.
Betrayal
배신
is unacceptable.
받아 들일 수 없습니다.
People often think otherwise,
사람들은 종종 다르게 생각하지만,
but my first
하지만 내 첫 번째
and most cherished son…
그리고 가장 소중한 아들..
has always been Hanmin.
언제나 한민이였습니다.
I can't believe this brat.
난 이 새끼를 믿을 수가 없어.
You'd think she was robbed.
당신은 그녀가 강도를 당했다고 생각할 것입니다.
Jeez.
이런.
Look at all these flashy clothes.
이 화려한 옷들을 보세요.
Gosh, this will fall apart as soon as you wear it.
맙소사, 이건 무너질 거야 입자마자.
This room is a mess.
이 방은 엉망이에요.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
She must be sweeping up all the dirt in the world with these.
그 사람이 쓸고 있는 게 틀림없어 세상의 모든 흙을 이것으로.
Gross.
역겨운.
Ripped jeans…
찢어진 청바지…
What are you doing in my room?
내 방에서 뭐 하는 거야?
Jeez.
이런.
I said, what are you doing in my room?
내 방에서 뭐하고 있니?
I was just stopping by and…
방금 들렀는데…
Stop it.
그만하세요.
What's wrong with your arm?
팔에 무슨 문제가 있나요?
I injured it recently.
최근에 부상을 입었어요.
So it hurts?
그래서 아파요?
SHINING PINK BOLERO RAGLAN SLEEVE CARDIGAN
샤이닝 핑크 볼레로 래글런 슬리브 카디건
CROPPED TEE, WIDE JEANS POPULAR SKINCARE
크롭티, 와이드 진 인기 스킨케어
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
Hey.
여기요.
No grown-up should let their belly hang out like that.
어른이 놔두면 안 돼 그들의 배는 그렇게 늘어져 있습니다.
Well…
음…
Do you think you can help me out?
당신이 나를 도와줄 수 있을 것 같아요?
Truth is,
진실은,
I'm looking to adopt a more youthful style.
입양하려고 해요 좀 더 젊은 스타일.
Why?
왜?
Are you trying to change your look to land a husband?
표정을 바꾸려고 하시나요? 남편을 얻으려고?
Just shut up and do it for the money.
그냥 닥치고 돈 때문에 하세요.
First off,
우선,
let's do something about this lifeless hair.
뭔가 하자 이 생명없는 머리카락에 대해.
Hello there.
안녕.
So have you decided?
그래서 결정하셨나요?
I…
나는…
Allow me to make a recommendation then.
그럼 제가 추천을 하도록 하겠습니다.
Just a moment.
잠시만요.
HAIR STYLES FOR WOMEN IN 30S
30대 여성을 위한 헤어스타일
How about something like this?
이런 건 어때요?
To accentuate the mature charm of a woman in her thirties--
성숙한 매력을 강조하기 위해 30대 여성의--
She's 20.
그녀는 20살이에요.
Pardon?
죄송해요?
I'm 20.
저는 20살이에요.
Sure. Just a moment.
물론이죠. 잠시만요.
This will accentuate the charm of Gen X.
이는 X세대의 매력을 더욱 부각시킬 것이다.
What do you think about this style?
이 스타일에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
She'll go with that one.
그녀는 그 사람과 함께 갈 것입니다.
Sure.
확신하는.
The final test happens after the hair and makeup.
최종 테스트가 진행됩니다 헤어와 메이크업을 마친 후.
The final test?
마지막 테스트?
FATEFUL ENCOUNTERS VIDEOS, DVDS, COMICS, NOVELS
운명적인 만남 비디오, DVD, 만화, 소설
I never fail to get carded at movie theaters and video stores.
나는 카드를 받는 데 결코 실패하지 않습니다 영화관 및 비디오 상점
You'll know you're passing for 20 when you get carded.
당신은 20을 통과한다는 것을 알게 될 것입니다 카드를 받았을 때.
Welcome.
환영.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
MUST BE 19 OR OVER TO RENT
임대하려면 19세 이상이어야 합니다.
TO YOU FROM ME
나로부터 당신에게
I really have to watch this tonight.
오늘 밤에는 이거 꼭 봐야 해요.
You'll let me take it, won't you?
내가 가져가게 해줄 거지, 그렇지?
No.
아니요.
I've also been waiting for tonight for a long time.
나도 오늘 밤을 기다렸어 오랫동안.
I grabbed it first.
제가 먼저 잡아봤습니다.
I don't think so.
나는 그렇게 생각하지 않습니다.
- Sir.
- 선생님.
TO YOU FROM ME
나에게서 당신에게
I'm going to
나는 갈 것이다
need to check your ID, miss.
신분증을 확인해야 해요, 아가씨.
This isn't meant for minors.
이는 미성년자를 위한 것이 아닙니다.
I wish you a lovely, passionate night by yourself.
나는 당신에게 사랑스러운 것을 기원합니다 혼자서 열정적인 밤.
Hormones run rampant at your age.
당신의 나이에는 호르몬이 만연합니다.
Was she talking about me?
그녀가 나에 대해 이야기하고 있었나요?
This is a masterpiece.
이것은 걸작입니다.
It is.
그것은.
It's a masterpiece of film.
영화의 걸작입니다.
It is with unbiased eyes.
편견 없는 눈으로 말입니다.
SEJIN HIGH SCHOOL
세진고등학교
1997 HANMIN RECRUITMENT WRITTEN EXAM FOR FEMALE HIGH SCHOOL GRADUATES
1997년 한민 채용 필기시험 여자 고등학교 졸업생의 경우
RESIDENT REGISTRATION CARD HONG JANG-MI
주민등록카드 홍장미
EXAM ID: 505 NAME: HONG JANG-MI
시험 ID: 505 이름: 홍장미
1ST PERIOD: COMMERCIAL ECONOMICS 2ND PERIOD: ACCOUNTING PRINCIPLES
1학기: 상업경제학 2학기: 회계원칙
ACCOUNTING PRINCIPLES
회계 원칙
1997 HANMIN FEMALE STAFF RECRUITMENT INTERVIEW
1997년 한민 여성직원 채용 인터뷰
The top and bottom scorers are interviewing together.
최고 및 최하위 득점자 같이 인터뷰 중이에요.
Hong Jang-mi got 297 on the written exam.
홍장미는 필기시험에서 297점을 받았다.
You only got the last accounting question wrong.
당신은 마지막을 얻었습니다 회계 질문이 잘못되었습니다.
Meanwhile,
한편,
Kang Eun-joo got a score of 210…
강은주 210점 획득…
I mean, 21 points.
즉, 21점입니다.
What's the point of interviewing?
인터뷰의 요점은 무엇입니까?
You should never hire the top scorer.
최고 득점자를 고용해서는 안됩니다.
What use would we have with a young, smart woman?
우리가 무슨 소용이 있겠어? 젊고 똑똑한 여자랑?
She's young but looks old.
그녀는 어리지만 늙어보이네요.
She'll never be carded on cigarette runs.
그녀는 담배를 피울 때 결코 카드를 받지 않을 것입니다.
- Ji-eun. - Yes?
- 지은이. - 예?
You worked under Deputy Manager Kim. I know him well.
김 차장 밑에서 일하셨는데요. 나는 그를 잘 안다.
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
- Ms. Lee Eun-yeong? - Yes?
- 이은영씨? - 예?
Do you prefer it boneless or with the bone?
뼈 없는 걸 선호하시나요? 아니면 뼈로?
- Ms. Seo Eun-su. - Yes?
- 서은수씨. - 예?
You're a former Miss Chunhyang?
전직 미스 춘향이신가요?
I was first runner-up.
저는 첫 번째 준우승자였습니다.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
- Let's wrap up. - Sure.
- 마무리합시다. - 확신하는.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
I wasn't asked a single question.
나는 단 하나의 질문도 받지 않았습니다.
Candidate 504 next to me wasn't, either.
내 옆에 있는 504번 후보도 그렇지 않았다.
You want a question?
질문이 있으신가요?
Bill Gates.
빌 게이츠.
You've heard of him, right?
그 사람에 대해 들어본 적 있죠?
What is the name of the company that Microsoft, led by Bill Gates,
회사 이름은 무엇입니까 빌게이츠가 이끄는 마이크로소프트는
recently invested 150 million dollars in?
최근에 1억 5천만 달러를 투자했나요?
Apple!
사과!
It's Apple.
애플이에요.
Steve Jobs recently came back on as CEO.
스티브 잡스가 최근 CEO로 복귀했습니다.
Ms. Kang Eun-joo,
강은주 선생님,
what a thoughtful response.
정말 사려 깊은 답변이네요.
You may all leave.
모두 떠나셔도 됩니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
This way.
이쪽으로.
Come on now.
지금 어서.
It's time to leave.
이제 떠날 시간이다.
I didn't get that last accounting question wrong.
나는 그것을 마지막으로 얻지 못했습니다 회계 질문이 잘못되었습니다.
The question itself was wrong.
질문 자체가 틀렸습니다.
The answer wasn't in the multiple choice, so I wrote it down separately.
정답은 객관식에 없었는데, 그래서 따로 적어두었습니다.
Please don't tell me I was the only one who noticed
제발 말하지 마세요 눈치채는 사람은 나뿐이었지
the error in that question.
그 질문의 오류.
MEETING ROOM DO NOT ENTER
회의실 입력하지 마세요
She's just some 20-year-old commercial high school grad.
그녀는 이제 막 20살이에요 상업고등학교 졸업.
How dare she question the accuracy of our data?
그녀가 감히 질문을 하다니 우리 데이터의 정확성은?
The answer is 27. It's not one of the choices.
답은 27이다. 선택 사항 중 하나가 아닙니다.
What? Seriously?
무엇? 진지하게?
The Research Division is in charge of the exam questions.
연구부문 시험 문제를 담당하고 있습니다.
Ms. Go, you're in charge of proofreading. Did you slack off?
고씨는 교정을 담당하고 계십니다. 느슨해졌나요?
I submitted a report noting a question error,
보고서를 제출했습니다 질문 오류를 지적하고,
along with the solution and the correct answer.
솔루션과 함께 그리고 정답.
No, I've never received such a report.
아니요, 그런 보고를 받은 적이 없습니다.
I guess Old Maid Go's mind is slipping.
바둑할머니의 정신이 미끄러지는 것 같아요.
Have you gotten forgetful?
잊어버리셨나요?
Where did she write her answer though?
그런데 그녀는 답을 어디에 썼나요?
P. S.
피. 에스.
Please conduct a thorough review of exam questions next time.
철저한 검토를 부탁드립니다 다음 시험 문제
There.
거기.
What should we do about Hong Jang-mi?
홍장미 어떻게 해야 할까요?
Please input your exam ID number.
시험 ID 번호를 입력하세요.
Exam ID 505. Ms. Hong Jang-mi.
시험번호 505. 홍장미 선생님
Congratulations. You have passed.
축하합니다. 합격하셨습니다.
Damn straight.
젠장 똑바로.
You've reached Hong Keum-bo.
홍금보에 도착했습니다.
Is this the X-file?
이게 X파일이야?
The operation will last three months.
수술은 3개월간 지속될 예정이다.
We're the only ones who know about this in the office.
우리뿐이야 사무실에서 이것에 대해 아는 사람.
If things go awry, I'll be shamed and forced to quit.
일이 잘못되면, 부끄러워서 그만둬야겠습니다.
I'll have to kiss my pension goodbye.
연금에 작별 인사를 해야겠습니다.
I notified the office
사무실에 알렸어요
that you'll be on a long-term business trip in the countryside.
네가 장기적으로 있을 거라고 시골로 출장.
These are background check reports
신원조사 보고서입니다
on the three Yehppee candidates and President Kang's close acquaintances.
세 명의 Yehppee 후보에 대해 그리고 강 회장의 측근들.
Who's the new CEO of Hanmin?
한민 신임 대표이사는 누구?
Is it Oh Deok-gyu, Chairman Kang's son-in-law?
오덕규인가? 강회장의 사위?
I thought it'd be him too, but apparently not.
나도 그 사람일 거라고 생각했는데, 하지만 분명히 그렇지 않습니다.
It's an external hire.
외부 채용입니다.
- Who? - I believe he's from overseas.
- WHO? - 내 생각에는 그 사람이 해외에서 온 것 같아요.
Oh, I almost forgot.
아, 거의 잊을 뻔했어요.
This is what you asked for.
이것이 당신이 요청한 것입니다.
CONFIRMATION OF RESIDENCE: SEOUL CITY DORMITORY FOR SINGLE FEMALE WORKERS
거주지 확인 : 서울특별시 미혼 여성 근로자를 위한 기숙사
RESIDENT NAME: HONG JANG-MI
주민 이름: 홍장미
SEOUL CITY DORMITORY FOR SINGLE FEMALE WORKERS
서울시립기숙사 미혼 여성 근로자를 위한
WELCOME TO SEOUL CITY DORMITORY
서울시립기숙사에 오신 것을 환영합니다
Hello.
안녕하세요.
It's nice to meet you all.
모두 만나서 반가워요.
I'm Kim Nam-ju, your residential advisor.
여러분의 주거상담사 김남주 입니다.
RESIDENTIAL ADVISOR KIM NAM-JU
주거지도사 김남주
SEOUL CITY DORMITORY FOR SINGLE FEMALE WORKERS
서울시립기숙사 미혼 여성 근로자를 위한
Welcome to the Seoul City Dormitory for Single Female Workers.
서울시립기숙사에 오신 것을 환영합니다 미혼 여성 근로자를 위한.
We're happy you're here.
당신이 여기 있어서 기뻐요.
You'll be required to pay a deposit of 620,000 won
비용을 지불해야 합니다. 보증금 62만원
and a monthly rent of 24,000 won.
월세는 24,000원 입니다.
Eligibility is limited
자격이 제한되어 있습니다
to unmarried women under 29
29세 미만 미혼 여성에게
who work in Seoul and earn less than 15 million annually.
서울에서 일하는 사람 그리고 연간 1,500만 달러 미만의 수익을 얻습니다.
We will do our very best to provide a safe living environment
우리는 최선을 다할 것입니다 안전한 생활환경을 제공하기 위해
until the day you're able to save up and find a place of your own.
저축할 수 있는 그날까지 그리고 자신만의 자리를 찾아보세요.
However!
하지만!
All rules must be observed.
모든 규칙을 준수해야 합니다.
Curfew after midnight.
자정 이후에는 통금 시간이 적용됩니다.
No visitors allowed under any circumstances.
방문자는 허용되지 않습니다 어떤 상황에서도.
This is a women-only residence.
여성 전용 레지던스입니다.
Don't ever forget that.
그것을 절대 잊지 마세요.
Applause.
박수 갈채.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Room 301?
301호?
Me too.
저도요.
- Hello. - Hi.
- 안녕하세요. - 안녕.
It's you, the top exam scorer!
시험 최고 득점자는 바로 당신입니다!
I'm Room 301 too.
나도 301호야.
It's you,
바로 당신이에요
"Apple."
"애플."
They said each room would have four people.
방마다 있다고 하더군요 네 사람이 있을 거예요.
Who are we missing?
우리는 누구를 놓치고 있나요?
I heard earlier
아까 들었어
that everybody moved out because of the queen bee here.
다들 이사 갔다고 여기 여왕벌 때문이에요.
I heard she works at the head office as an assistant.
그녀가 일한다고 들었어 본사에서 보조원으로.
Why do you even want to live in a dorm?
왜 기숙사에 살고 싶어?
Must you take it that far?
그렇게까지 해야 합니까?
The hidden link between Yehppee and me lives there.
숨겨진 링크 Yehppee와 나 사이에 거기 살고 있어요.
The three Yehppee candidates are
세 명의 Yehppee 후보는 다음과 같습니다.
So Gyeong-dong, Bang Jin-mok, and Cha Jung-il.
소경동, 방진목, 차정일.
YEHPPEE CANDIDATES
예피 후보자
President Kang
강 대표
communicated with Yehppee, the whistleblower, at the office.
Yehppee와 대화를 나눴습니다. 내부 고발자, 사무실에서.
He told me that his assistant kept track of where he was
그는 나에게 그의 조수가 말했다 그가 어디에 있는지 계속 추적했다
and whom he met with at all times.
그리고 그는 항상 만난 사람입니다.
So his assistant will have to know
그래서 그의 조수는 알아야 할 것입니다
who Yehppee is.
예피가 누구죠?
But
하지만
I'm sure she doesn't know that she's an important witness.
나는 그녀가 모른다고 확신한다 그녀가 중요한 증인이라는 걸요.
GO BOK-HEE PERSONAL ASSISTANT TO THE PRESIDENT
고복희 대통령 개인 비서
LIVES IN ROOM 301 AT THE FEMALE WORKERS' DORM
301호실에 거주 여성 근로자 기숙사에서
Let's go inside.
안으로 들어가자.
Who's Hong Keum-bo?
홍금보는 누구인가?
"Hong Jang-mi's Outfit Inspiration Book for a 20-Year-Old."
"홍장미의 의상 영감북 20세용."
From Hong Jang-mi. To my sister, Hong Keum-bo.
홍장미에서. 내 여동생 홍금보에게.
Why are you digging through my stuff?
왜 내 물건을 뒤지는 거야?
Wait.
기다리다.
I know that face.
나는 그 얼굴을 안다.
SPECIAL THANKS TO SHIN YU-NA AND PARK JUNG-PYO FOR THEIR APPEARANCES
신유나님께 특별히 감사드립니다. 그리고 박정표의 출연
UNDERCOVER MISS HONG
언더커버 미스홍
Befriend that assistant and just get the intel you need.
그 조수와 친구가 되어 보세요 필요한 정보를 얻으세요.
Then focus on finding Yehppee.
그럼 Yehppee를 찾는 데 집중하세요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I'm Hong Jang-mi.
홍장미입니다.
Hey, Ms. Hong! Commercial high! Uniform girl! You!
안녕하세요, 홍 선생님! 상업적 최고! 교복소녀! 당신!
You'll deliver it safely and promptly.
안전하고 신속하게 배송해 드리겠습니다.
I'm supposed to be Ms. Go Bok-hee's successor?
아마도 Ms. 고복희 후계자?
You, lock the door.
당신, 문을 잠그세요.
Who says the new president will have a new assistant?
새 대통령이 누구라고 새 어시스턴트가 생기나요?
I'm the newest member of Hanmin Investment & Securities,
저는 최신 회원입니다 한민투자증권
Shin Jung-woo.
신정우.
If I'd known that Shin Jung-woo would be joining,
알았다면 신정우가 합류한다고
I'd never have set foot in Hanmin, undercover my ass.
나는 한민에 발을 들여본 적도 없고, 내 엉덩이를 숨겨라.
You know him?
그 사람을 아시나요?
And shared a passionate romance?
열정적인 로맨스를 나누셨나요?
Subtitle translation by: Justin S. Kim
자막 번역: Justin S. Kim